以下是前情提要
This is what you missed last week on Shameless.
走吧  利普  我要回家了
Come on, Lip, I'm going home.
你昨晚让人在轻轨上用手指操了你
You let some dude finger you last night on the EL?
被你说得好肮脏
You make it sound so filthy.
而且也不是随便哪个人
And he's not just any dude.
没错  是你男朋友的哥哥
No, he's your boyfriend's brother!
罗比  是我
Yo, Robbie, it's me.
对于凯文·鲍尔  我把我珍爱的艾莱伯酒吧
To Kevin Ball, I leave my beloved
-留给他  -什么
- "Alibi Room." - What?
两年期  每年你每月
Why don't you send me $500 a month
-给我500美金  -好的
- for two years. - Okay.
不给她们工钱谁也别想上床
No one's getting laid till they get paid.
婊子我有了
Look, I got the labor force already.
只欠客源和一个场所
All I need is the clientele and a location.
-这两样你都有  -我想入伍
- You've got both. - I want to enlist.
-菲利普  -是利普
- Phillip. - It's Lip.
现在起叫你加拉格  上车
It's just Gallagher now. Get on.
我要你弄断我的腿  我需要保险金
I want you to break my leg. I need the insurance money.
只有这样  我才能做移植手术
It's the only way I'll be able to pay for the transplant.
竟然跟自己的女儿都不匹配
My own daughter isn't even a match!
-女儿  -算了
- Daughter? - Oh, fuck it.
滚出去
Get...out!
我受够了别人告诉我
You know, I'm getting pretty damn tired of everybody
该去哪里  该做什么了
telling me where I should be and what I should be doing.
那就别给他们机会说啊
Well, then, stop making them have to!
他妈的成熟起来
Grow the fuck up!
我要给我女儿点一杯啤酒
I need a-a beer for my daughter here.
无耻家庭
第四季第五集
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：  爱卿遛小鸟   重案组李Sir   企鹅三星带花
■
翻译：  扎克不渣   拉图   Greentie   青椒   君君
时间轴：  大喷子   芝麻圆子
■
校对： Greentie   爱卿遛小鸟
后期： 加森          总监： 落
■
想知道我为什么选这个角落吗
You're wondering why I picked this corner?
-没兴趣  -因为
- I'm really not. - Well, it's 'cause--
我和麦克在一起的时候你就打电话过来
You call me when I'm with Mike.
发短信给我
Text me when I'm with Mike.
要不干脆省了我这个中间人
How about we just cut out the middleman, which is me,
你就直接上了你弟弟得了
and you can fuck your brother?
我要带你去那里
I'm bringing you there.
不  你走你的阳关道  我
No. You're going on with your life, I'm--
你是说汽车旅馆  真有你的
Oh, this motel? It's classy.
钟点房  够刺激
Rooms by the hour. That's why it's fun.
还记得上次
You know how last time
我让你不要再发短信给我
when I told you to stop texting me
结果却跟你上了床吗
and it turned into sex?
这次可不一样了
This isn't that.
我不知道为什么过了这么久
I don't know why it took me this long
我才开始厌恶自己
to start hating myself,
但我总算到了这个阶段了
but I got there.
这感觉糟透了
It's a shitty feeling.
我不是在惩罚你或者责怪你
I'm not punishing you or blaming you.
我只想结束这件事
I just really need this to end.
辛迪·林恩汽车旅馆
绝不分心
菲利普·加拉格
Phillip Gallagher?
是我  外面是谁
Yeah, who's asking?
迪尔伯恩堡军事警察
Fort Dearborn Military Police.
请你走出隔间好吗
Can you step out of the stall please?
那个  我可能还得忙活一会儿
You know, I'm gonna be busy for a while,
要是你想给我擦屁股的话  请进
but you can join me if you want to wipe my ass.
等等  搞什么飞机  伙计
Wait, what the fuck, man?
中士  等等
Sergeant, wait!
你是菲利普·加拉格
You're Phillip Gallagher?
老天  究竟干嘛呢这是
Jesus, what the hell's going on?
还是说你们就是热衷于看男人拉屎呢
Or do you get off on watching guys taking a dump?
这是你的社保号码吗
Is that your social security number?
去你的  好吧  是的  是的
Blow me. Okay, yeah, yeah, yeah.
我操
Fuck.
你认识这名男子吗
Do you know this man?
不认识  以前从未见过
No, I've never seen him before in my life.
知道他怎么弄到
Any idea how he got a hold of
你的名字和社保号码的吗
your name and social security number?
不知道  不过这事挺吓人的
No, but it's pretty scary, you know?
我感觉自己深深地侵犯了
I'm feeling pretty fucking violated over here.
他  他犯了什么事
What's he, uh, what's he wanted for?
显然  他冒充了你
For impersonating you, apparently.
还有盗窃政府财产未遂
Also for attempted theft of government property
以及未请假擅自离队
and being away without leave.
难怪了  他企图偷什么
Wow, no shit. What did he try and steal?
直升飞机  地空导弹
Helicopter. Surface-to-air missile.
-军用四角裤  -中士
- Army issue boxer bris. - Sergeant!
加拉格先生  我可能会需要你作证
Mr. Gallagher, we may need you to testify.
保持联系
We'll be in touch.
稍息[也有"放心"之意]  先生
Well, at ease, gentlemen.
我一直想说这句话呢
I've always wanted to say that.
这就是了
So this is it.
这就是我老爸住的地方
This is where my dad lives.
总体来看  还挺宽敞
In all it's grandeur.
没人在家
No one's home?
还以为我会见到我的兄弟姐妹呢
Thought I might meet my brothers and sisters.
那个  他们很忙
Yeah, well, they're pretty busy.
不管了  我们该上路了
Anyway, we should hit the road.
是时候找那该死的保险公司
Time to find out what this
算算我这脚值多少钱了
foot is worth to the damn insurance company.
等等
Oh, wait, wait.
给你
Here.
脚趾专用
For your toes!
来吧  坐下
Come on, sit down.
希望他们这个季节不会再伤我们的心了
Hopefully, they won't break our hearts again this season.
那个  我有话要说
So, um, there's something I have to say.
你和我  我们之间有
You and me, we have...
一种羁绊
a connection.
我是说  上个星期我还企图把你弄上床
I mean, last week I was trying to get you into the sack.
在当时那种情况下完全可以理解
It's understandable under the circumstances.
我当时还想  "这一炮肯定会很爽"
I thought, "The sex is gonna be amazing"
之后我就发现你是我老爸
And then I found out you were my dad,
然后我就  调整了下心情
so that was, like... an adjustment.
应该的
Sure.
我这一生
My whole life,
一直在寻找一个老爸一样的人
I've been looking for a daddy.
店铺打烊前勾搭上我的那个老头
The old men who'd get lucky with me at last call,
在马尼拉遇上的疱疹贝斯手
the bass player who got herpes in Manila,
现在  我终于  找到了你
And now, at last, I have you.
只是
Only--
什么
What?
你找我并不是因为
You didn't come find me
你需要另一个女儿
because you need another daughter.
你只是需要一个肝  对吗  我会帮你找一个的
You just need a liver, right? And I'm gonna help you find one,
不过要是我们缘尽于此
but if that's all this is...
-不  不是  -那我
- No, no. - Then I--
不
No.
没错  起初我确实只把你看作一个器官农场
I mean, yes, initially I sort of looked at you as an organ farm,
但是当你知道我们是家人之后
but when you figured out we were family,
你没有像我其他孩子那样对待我
You didn't treat me like the rest of my kids--
那帮小崽子们大难临头各自飞
rats leaving a sinking ship.
而我也不会责怪你
And, hell, I wouldn't have blamed you.
因为你一直陪在我身边
But you stuck around.
给予我希望
You gave me hope.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我真不喜欢哭
I hate to cry. Oh.
我要不是磕了药也会哭的
I'd be crying too if I wasn't so high.
走吧  老爸
Come on, daddy.
咱们给你弄钱去
Let's go get you some money, huh?
拉森路152号  我的午餐就是你
删除联系人
你来猜猜
Hey, you wanna guess.
猜什么
Guess what?
我们为你的生日准备了什么
What we're doing for your birthday.
去跳舞
Going dancing?
我是说  去跳伞
I mean, skydiving?
性爱俱乐部
Sex club?
我就知道  性爱俱乐部
I knew it. Sex club.
-我会穿我的情趣内衣  -要穿酒会礼服
- I'll wear my crotchless teddy. - Uh, cocktail attire.
穿暖和点  可能会有户外活动
Wear something warm in case we want to hang outside.
我从来没去过户外性爱俱乐部
Ah, I've never been to an outdoor sex club.
是吗  你猜怎么着
Oh, yeah, you know what?
提到浪漫有爱的活动  我想起我妈
Speaking of romantic, intimate getaways-- my mom.
她让我们今晚去烤肉
She wanted us to come grill tonight.
是吗
She did?
-太有心了  -是呀
- That's so nice. - Yeah.
就我们俩  还有罗比
So it's just us. And Robbie.
还有我父母  好吗
And my parents. Is that okay?
很好  当然了
Perfect. Sure.
我是酒吧的老板
I own the Alibi Room!
这是个酒吧  你可能不知道
It's a bar, which you may not know,
因为你们架子挡住招牌了
because your fucking scaffolding is covering the sign!
你的工人说
Your guy said that--
你的  你的
Your--your--
打扰一下
Excuse me!
你能不能先别钻了
Can you please stop jackhammering
给我一分钟  谢了
for one minute? Thank you!
你的工人说这个架子是为了检查
Your guys said the scaffolding is to check the building
-大楼上有没有松的砖块什么的  -是的
- for loose bricks or something. - Correct.
那你们为什么要钻人行道
Yeah, then why are you digging up the sidewalk?
要更新下水管道
New sewer line.
我靠人潮做生意的  好吗
I depend on walk-in business, all right?
顾客看到招牌  他们会想
Customers see the sign, they go,
"这家酒吧不错
"Hey, that's a nice bar.
我想去喝一杯"
I want a drink there."
但是重要的是
Here's the important part.
他们得走人行道进来
They need the sidewalk to walk into my bar!
要修多久
How long?
什么
What?
这道要修几天
How long is it gonna be torn up?
一两天吗
A day or two?
六或七吧
More like six or seven.
七天
Seven days?
七周
Weeks.
操
Fuck!
-不是吧  -利普
- No way. - Lip!
你回来了
You're home!
是时候来看看你们了
Thought it was time I stopped by, check in.
-大学欲女们怎么样  -千姿百态
- How are the coeds? - Oh, it varies by coed.
-那是什么  -她的变态艺术品
- What's this? - Creepy art she's making
-因为他男朋友把她甩了  -男朋友
- 'Cause her boyfriend dumped her. - A boyfriend?
我在创造性地抒发自己
I'm expressing myself creatively.
你在照镜子数腋毛
You're counting underarm hair with a mirror.
来看看  新长了四根
Check it out, four new ones.
给我走开
Get off of me!
菲利普
Phillip!
太好了
How nice!
没人跟我说你要回来
No one told me you'd be home!
希拉  你怎么会在这儿
Sheila, wha-- what are you doing here?
问得好
Good question.
菲奥娜上班了
Well, Fiona's at work,
然后她要去麦克家烤肉
and then she has a barbecue at Mike's house,
我就说我很乐意帮忙照顾孩子们
and I said I'd be happy to watch the kids.
很好  那你和利亚姆要烛光晚餐吗
Nice, and you and Liam here having a candle-lit dinner?
这个
Well...
菲奥娜说我把约会对象带来
Fiona said it was okay if I had my date over.
已经是我们第四次约会了
It's actually our fourth date.
他很有趣
He's such an interesting man.
这是什么音乐
What's the music?
"部落暮色  梅诺米尼佛尔
"Tribal twilight: Recorded Songs
印第安部落音乐合集"
of the Menominee Indian Tribe."
我的豆煮玉米好了  稍等
That would be my succotash. Hold on.
好的
Okay.
玩儿去吧
There you go.
你们有伊恩的消息吗
Hey, um, you guys heard anything from Ian?
好几周都没有消息了  菲奥娜根本不在乎
Not for weeks. And Fiona doesn't even care.
军队那边呢  他们那边有什么消息吗
What about the U.S. Army. You hear anything from them?
我们找菲利普·加拉格
We're looking for Phillip Gallagher.
他在上大学
He's at college.
-没有  -跟军队有什么关系
- No. - Why the army?
-因为伊恩参军了  -酷
- 'Cause ian joined up. - Cool.
他够年龄吗
Is he old enough?
他用了我的名字跟社保号
No, he used my name and social when he signed up,
然后他企图偷一架直升机
and then he tried to steal a helicopter
还有其他东西  就逃跑了
and a bunch of other shit. Went awol.
直升机  屌爆了
Helicopter? Awesome.
-菲奥娜知道吗  -不  还不知道
- Does Fiona know? - No, not yet.
你知道他什么时候回来吗
You know when she's gonna be back?
她有时不回家
She doesn't always come home.
-都是希拉看孩子  -你可以打电话给她
- Lots of Sheila babysitting. - You could call her.
不了  这种消息打电话说
No, it's not the kind of news you want
不太合适
to deliver on the phone.
脑袋上插着牙签的
Hey, is that your boyfriend
是你男朋友吗
with the toothpicks in his head?
比较抽象  我称之为"针爱"
It's sort of abstract. I'm calling it "True love."
超变态
Super creepy.
有一天收藏家会出几百万买的
Collectors will pay millions for it one day.
一件黛比·加拉格的早期拼画作品
An early work from Debbie Gallagher's collage phase.
-晚点见  好吗  -你去哪
- I'll see you guys later, okay? - Where you going?
我出去打听一下伊恩的消息
I'm gonna go ask around about Ian.
看看有没有人有线索
See if anyone's heard from him.
-好的  -拜
- Okay. - Bye.
好像你懂艺术似的
Like you know anything about art.
好了  向左转
All right, turn to the left.
把腿抬起来
And raise the leg.
摆个苦逼的表情
Yeah, now make a sad face.
怎么  我现在看上去很开心吗
What, do I look happy?
天呐
Oh, man.
我真的以为你会临阵脱逃
Totally thought you were gonna wuss out on me on this,
就弄个微创骨折什么的  但是这个
come back with a hairline fracture, but this?
简直是杰作
This is a masterpiece.
这就像是世贸遗址的俯视图一样
I mean, this is like a aerial photo of ground zero.
你应该为自己骄傲
You should be very proud.
能拿到10万美元就好
Just tell me we can get 100 grand.
10万美元  没有问题
Oh, I'd say 100 "G"S, easy.
太好了
That's wonderful.
我马上就填表格
I am just going to get my hands on the forms.
她是目击者  对吧
She signs as a witness, right?
我们批准赔偿金  你16个月后就能拿到支票
We file the claim, and then you get a check in 16 months.
什么  16个月  不行  太长了
What--16 months? No, that's too long.
我的肝现在已经衰竭了
My liver is failing now.
我可以争取一个快速补偿金
Well, I can push for a quick settlement.
-有多快  -一年吧
- How quick. - A year?
弗兰克  他们不会随随便便就给你钱
Hey, Frank, they're not gonna just hand you the cash, okay?
忍忍吧  活下来
Suck it up and survive.
今晚跟我住  我照顾你
Stay with me tonight. I'll take care of you.
我需要更多小药丸
I'm gonna need more meds.
曼迪不在
Mandy ain't here.
正好  我想跟你谈谈
That's good, 'cause I came to talk to you.
你想干什么
The fuck you want?
你有伊恩的消息吗
You heard anything from Ian?
没有
No.
这事很重要
It's important.
就因为我跟他一起工作过
So you think I give a shit
你觉得我就会鸟这事
'cause I worked with the guy?
非要我把话说明白吗
You're gonna make me spell it out?
你他妈的到底想说什么
What the fuck you getting at?
没什么  我只是有些担心他罢了
Nothing, I'm just worried about him.
仅此而已
That's all.
反正我是没见到过他
Well, I haven't seen him.
一句话的功夫  有多难
How hard was that?
他犯事了
He in trouble?
犯什么事了
What kind of trouble?
我知道了告诉你
I'll tell you when I find out.
罗比  跟他们说说火鸡的事
Robbie, tell them what you were saying about the turkey.
-真要说  -火鸡
- Yeah? - Turkey?
我在俄勒冈州的泰德家作客时
When I was at Ted's in Oregon,
他要我试试他鼎鼎大名的炸火鸡
he wanted me to try his famous deep-fried turkey.
于是我们将一个倒满滚油的高压锅
So we put this hot oil pressure cooker thing
放在院子里
in the yard...
将火鸡放进去后  锅突然爆炸了
And put the turkey in, and it exploded.
他房子一半着了火
Set the entire side of his house on fire.
-不是吧  -弄得消防车什么的都来了
- No way. - Fire trucks, all that.
他们将火给扑灭了
They put the fire out,
房子还没什么大事
and the house was more or less okay.
但是后来我们在游泳池的旁边找到了火鸡
But then we saw the turkey by the swimming pool.
这事真是笑死人
This is really good.
-你都知道了  -扯下一根鸡腿
- Oh, you've heard this? - Pull a drumstick off
放在嘴里那么一尝
and try it...
味道还真是相当不错
And it was really, really good!
你能相信这事吗
Can you believe it?
爸把我搬去波特兰的事跟你说了吗
Did dad tell you how I want to move to Portland?
-没有啊  -这可有意思了
- No. - Oh, that's interesting.
因为他说他跟你谈过这件事
'Cause he said he spoke to you and you were the one
你说服他不要为我的行程出钱
who talked him out of writing the check to cover my move.
不  他没有向我提过你要搬去俄勒冈州的事
No, he didn't mention that you were moving to Oregon.
能不当着客人的面
Can we not do this
-谈论这件事吗  -谁是客人  菲奥娜吗
- with a guest here? - What, Fiona?
她基本上是一家人了  妈
She's practically family, mom.
听我说  罗比  我没有背着你
Look, Robbie, I haven't told dad anything
跟爸谈任何事情  好吗
that I haven't said to you, alright?
而且我觉得我们最好...
And I think it's a smart idea for--
我用不着事事向你请示汇报
I don't tell you what to do.
你要是想跟爸一起卖一辈子的杯子
And so if you want to sell cups for the rest of your life
整天坐在那套仿木办公桌后面
with dad, go for it, all right? Sit behind a fake wood desk
为了你的复式公寓跟道奇车拼命赚钱
all day and make payments on your duplex
只管去做  好吗
and your cool Dodge Challenger.
怎么  你这是在追逐梦想了  是不是
What, are you chasing your dreams, is that it?
结果怎么样  罗比
How's that working out, Robbie?
菲奥娜
Fiona...
能搭把手帮我拿些串肉扦吗
Can you give me a hand with the skewers?
-来了  -谢谢
- I'd love to. - Thanks.
那艘湖船晚上亮起灯来时可漂亮了
That lakeboat looks gorgeous at night, all lit up.
什么  什么湖船
What? What lakeboat?
-麦克说是给你生日...  -比尔
- Mike said for your birthday-- - Bill!
这是个惊喜
It was a surprise.
-我还以为...  -你儿子说得
- I thought it was-- - He made it
够明白了
perfectly clear.
该死  我很抱歉
Oh, shit, I'm sorry.
我会装作很惊讶的
I'll pretend I'm surprised.
事实上既然你提到了  听上去确实很有意思
And now that you mention it, it does sound fun.
相当不错
It's wonderful.
几年前我带南希去了一趟
I took Nancy there a few years ago.
真是浪漫极了
Aw, it was so romantic.
窗子旁边有张桌子
Got a table by the window.
外面也有坐的地方
There's seating on the outside,
但是真的很冷
But it gets pretty cold out there.
多穿点就好了
Just bring a warm coat.
当时舞池正热闹  好像还有个DJ
There's a lit dance floor and, I guess, a D.J.
不时还有乐队现场演出
Or a live band, depending.
我们就这么坐在桌子那...
We just sat at our table, got--
该死
God damn it!
-搞什么  -别打了  你们两个
- What? - Stop it, you two--
-住手  给我住手  -天呐
- Stop! Stop it, stop! - Oh, my god.
-滚你妈的  -别打了
- Fuck off! - Stop it!
-怎么了  -给我住手
- What happened? - Stop it.
你说什么了
What did you say?
一切都还好吗
Everything okay?
我在里面等着
I'll wait inside.
我想你最好回去
No, you should go.
麦克  我不知道他说了什...
Mike, I don't know what he sa--
别说了  走吧
Please, just go.
事实上  我去世的前夫
Actually, my deceased ex-husband
是个非常虔诚的基督徒
had very strong Christian beliefs,
我也会和他一起去教堂
and I would go to church with him.
但我得承认  我已经有很长一段时间没去了
But I've got to admit, it's been a while.
-我不是基督教徒  -什么
- I'm not a Christian. - What?
但... 但这是个供基督徒相亲的网站啊
But the--the website was christian-mingle.com.
这是个结识善良白人女性的好途径
Good way to meet nice white women.
我就把你这句话当成称赞吧
Oh, well, I'll take that as a compliment.
你可真是秀色可餐
My eyes enjoy you.
别让我打搅到你们
Don't let me interrupt.
我在冰箱里藏了些大麻食品
I stashed some THC edibles in the freezer.
我得...
I gotta--
你叫什么来着  爬·大麻
What was your name again? Climbing Weed?
奔跑·树
Running Tree.
你是印第安人  不是印度人
You're Indian? The feather, not the dot?
他是个梅诺米尼人  弗兰克
He's a Menominee Indian, Frank.
我们都是  事实上
We both are, actually.
我的曾祖母曾经被一个梅诺米尼战士强奸过
My great-grandmother was raped by a Menominee warrior,
我现在正在学习他们的文化呢
and I'm learning all about the culture.
这国家哪还有得说
Isn't this a great country?
整一个充斥着强奸色彩的大熔炉
Just one, big, rapey melting pot.
弗兰克  我们正在吃晚餐呢
Frank, we're just-- we're having dinner.
没事  我不吃
No, I'm fine.
我能问你一个敏感的问题吗
Can I ask you a delicate question?
多谢
Thanks.
在印第安保护区
On the Indian reservation,
你们喝酒喝得昏天黑地
you people drink yourselves unconscious,
可怎么从来没有印第安人需要肝移植的
but I never hear of an Indian getting a liver transplant.
-究竟为什么  -政府不肯出钱
- Why is that? - Government won't pay for it.
所以我们用汗蒸小屋来治病
So we use a sweat lodge.
它是一种仪式
It's a ceremony.
它能净化你的肝脏  你的脾脏
It cleans your liver, your spleen.
将你的灵魂置于大神之前
Opens your soul to the great spirit.
感觉非常好
And it's a real high.
将你脂细胞中的毒素释放干净
Releases the toxins in your fat cells.
就像磕了奥施康定一样  极嗨
It's like snorting oxy, man. It's beautiful.
你觉得这对我的肝有效果吗
Do--do you think it would work for my liver?
-我的身体快玩完了  -当然
- This baby's on its last legs. - No question.
但我现在住在公寓里  没地方建小屋
But I live in a condo. No place to build a lodge.
你可以在我的院子里建
Well, you could use my yard.
没关系吗
That would be all right with you?
我觉得这个点子太棒了
Oh, I think it would be just wonderful.
我已经有段时间没做过这种事了
Hmm. It's been a while.
管他的  咱们动手吧
But, hell yes. Let's do it.
-去他妈的西药  -致大汗一场
- Fuck Western medicine. - To sweatin' it out.
致汗蒸排毒
To sweating it out.
To sweatin' it out!
这是什么
What is that?
我要把这个牌子放在外面
I'm gonna put this sign outside
这样大伙就知道从后门进来了
so people know to come in the back.
"这边射"
"进"这个字可不是这么拼  你知道吧
You realize that's not how you spell "Come," Right?
-操  -他看见你了
- Shit. - Baby, he saw you.
艾伦
Alan.
你还好吗  朋友  你需要点什么
How are you, my friend? What can I get you?
那就来说说看吧  首先我需要
Well, let's see. I'll start with two
法律规定的每月500块
legally-mandated monthly payments of $500 each.
我也想把钱给你啊
And I'd love to give them to you,
但这个酒吧在财务上就像个大黑洞
But this bar is a financial black hole.
现在市政部门把前门给堵了
And now the city has blocked our front door,
人们都以为我们关门了
So people think we are closed.
我保证资金一旦周转过来  就会给你钱
The minute we turn it around you'll get paid, I promise.
你们可是继承了我父亲的遗产呢
Well, you're keeping up with my father's legacy.
-我们在努力  -辜负了我的信任
- We're trying. - Violating my trust
把我当猴耍
and screwing me over!
他即使死了都不肯让我好过
Even dead, he fucks me!
1000块  明天就要  明白吗
$1,000, tomorrow. Understand?
他是在威胁我们吗
Was he threatening us?
是吧  他会用他的娘们儿手腕把我们揍死的
Yeah, he's gonna beat us to death with his limp wrist.
不过他老爸的枪支都留给他了呢
Though he did inherit his father's gun collection.
那倒是
True.
他老爸可是个高利贷大亨
And his daddy was a loan shark.
他或许也学了那么一两招
He might have learNed a few tricks of the trade.
到目前为止  今天真是糟透了
So far, this day has sucked ass.
我们要找什么线索
What kind of clues are we looking for?
比如伊恩的某位神秘朋友
Uh, a friend of Ian we don't know about,
地址啊  什么信息都行
an address. Anything, really.
他真的偷了一架直升机吗
He really stole a helicopter?
-听上去不像是伊恩的作风  -是不像
- Doesn't sound like Ian. - No.
你很担心吗
You're worried?
是啊  是啊  你要知道
Yeah. Yeah, you know,
我们最好赶在军方之前找到他
it would be nice to find him before the army does.
我明天放学后可以帮忙找他
I can help look for him after school tomorrow.
如果你能跟曼迪谈谈就再好不过了
It would be great if you could talk to Mandy.
你不想跟她谈谈吗
You don't want to?
她在生你的气  对吧
She's mad at you, isn't she?
是啊  我们重新联系了  但情况比较复杂
Yeah, we reconnected, and things got complicated.
-你们做爱了吗  -什么
- Did you have sex? - What?
也不是一定要告诉我
You don't have to tell me.
是的  但是...
Yeah, but...
那也没什么大不了的
You know, it was no big deal.
如果不是性的问题  那是什么问题
If it wasn't sex, then what was the problem?
其他一切都有问题
Everything else.
告诉我你对麦克说了什么
Tell me what you told Mike!
实话  他应该知道才对
The truth! He needed to know.
是为了他好对吗  真慷慨呀你
Oh, that was for his sake? How generous.
我帮了你一个忙  好吗
I did you a favor, okay?
去你妈的
Fuck you.
你根本不想跟他在一起
You don't want to be with him.
你他妈对我一无所知
You don't know shit about me.
该死
Shit!
你他妈在跟我开玩笑吧
You've got to be kidding me.
你能别晃荡着鸡巴乱跑吗
Hey, you mind not swinging that shit around?
你会伤到人的
You're gonna fuckin' hurt someone.
-这都是你的错  -我的错
- This is your fault! - Mine?
走几步都能被婊子绊倒
I'm practically tripping over these bitches.
我要她们立刻都滚蛋
I want them gone, now!
我就离开了十分钟而已
I was gone ten fucking minutes!
我是米奇  你要不要入伙
Yo, it's Mickey. In or out?
我说过了  我入伙
I told you, I'm in.
我只是还不想跟我妻子讨论
I'm just not looking forward to discussing it with my wife.
晚点再打给你
I'll call you back.
宝贝
Baby?
-什么事  -你还记得我们之前谈到过
- Yeah? - You know how we were talking about
利用斯坦的公寓多挣些钱的事吗
using Stan's apartment to generate some income?
租出去嘛
Rent it out.
或者  我们可以开展一项新业务
Or, we could open up another business.
鉴于现在旧业务运作得"真好"呢
Since this one is going so well.
你知道办个营业执照有多贵吗
You know how expensive it is to get a business license?
或者我们根本不需要
Unless we don't need one.
斯瓦特娜和她的姐妹们歇工了
Svetlana and her girls are out of work--
等等  等一下
Wait. Wait a minute.
你是想开妓院吗
Do you want to open a whorehouse?
不  当然不是了
No, of course not!
只是打飞机而已
Just a rub and tug.
就像是按摩  不过更爽而已
It's a massage with a happy ending.
我知道打飞机是什么玩意儿
I know what a rub and tug is.
那些姑娘是受过训练的专业妓师
Those girls are traiNed professionals.
和酒吧相比  那可是纯盈利的
And compared to this place, it's pure profit.
宝贝  听着  我们是这个操蛋社会的受害者
Baby, look, we are victims of a society that squeezes
把中低阶层的人民压榨得要死  毁了我们的生意
the lower middle class, screws up our businesses
外面都是施工的手提钻
Because of jackhammers
又是税收和各种管理条例
and taxes and regulations
以及一堆没必要的文件
and unnecessary paperwork,
简直是逼我们做违法的生意
basically forces us to do illegal shit.
我就要成为4个孩子的爹了
Now I'm having four kids!
如果那意味着我得利用一些俄国妓女
And if that means I've got to turn out some RussIan whores
来养家  并继续追求美国梦
to feed my family and pursue the American dream,
我就会那样做
that's how it's gotta be!
我本来想说的是  我觉得那是个好主意
I was gonna say I think it's a great idea.
-真的吗  -是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
我们赶快让那些贱人们开工吧
Let's get those bitches tuggin'.
好了
There you go.
你这么悉心照顾我  对我意义重大
It means a lot, you looking after me like this.
我是个走运的公共...  老天
I am a lucky public-oh, jesus chr--ow!
嘿  小心点
Hey, be careful!
不 没事的  没事的
No, no, it's fine. It's fine.
-他不是有意的  - 不是
- He didn't mean to. - No.
是吧  小恰
Did you, Chuckles?
有趣的孩子
Funny kid.
-跟家人在一起的感觉真好  -确实
- It's nice to be with family. - It sure is.
早上好
Morning.
早上好  现在或许不是把伊恩的事
Morning. Oh, probably not a good time
告诉菲奥娜的好时机
to tell Fiona about Ian.
为什么
And why is that?
她和麦克分手了  我听到她和小维说话
Her and Mike broke up. Heard her talking to V.
刚分手时  女人是无法承受坏消息的
And after a breakup, a woman's not in the mood for bad news.
嗨  麦克
Hi, Mike.
我很抱歉连留了15通语音消息
Sorry for the 15 stalker voicemails.
我觉得你不太想看到我出现在办公室吧
I'm assuming you don't want to see my face in the office,
但我或许该过去拿一下我的东西
but maybe I should come get my stuff.
我真的不太确定如何处理这事
I'm not really sure how to handle it,
给我打电话吧  如果你...
So, uh, call me if, uh... Yeah.
昨晚似乎过得不怎么开心呀
Doesn't sound like a fun night.
我一闭上眼睛  就会看到麦克
Every time I close my eyes, I see Mike.
他看我时的那种样子
The way he looked at me.
昨晚  在艾莱柏酒吧工作了16个小时后
Last night, after a 16-hour work day at the Alibi,
小凯和我热了些薯饼当晚饭
Kev and I heated tater tots for dinner.
当我从微波炉里取出那些
And when I picked up those little brown lumps
棕色的小饼时  小凯用这种表情看着我
out of the microwave, Kev made this face.
你谈到麦克时  也是这种表情
That's how you look when you talk about Mike.
-什么  -麦克是个好男人
- What? - Mike's a nice guy,
但你向来都没那么喜欢他
But you were never that into him.
我从没露出过这种表情
I have never made that face.
麦克就是可怜的薯饼
Mike is a tater tot.
他一定会开除我的
There's no way that he doesn't fire me.
更别提  那公司的老板还是他爸
Not to mention, his dad owns the company,
而且他昨晚也在场
and he was there last night.
我已经习惯了有稳定收入的生活
I was getting so used to a steady paycheck.
不用优惠券去买杂货
Groceries without coupons,
买瓶装酒而不是盒装酒
and wine in a bottle instead of a box.
你觉得他们会付我上周的薪水吗  还是直接赶我走
You think they'll pay me for last week, or just stiff me?
还有医疗保险
oh, health insurance.
我们得在他们取消前赶去牙医那里
I mean, we have to get to the dentist before they cancel it.
我就说吧
Told you.
早啊
Morning.
我了个去  你什么时候回来的
Holy shit! When did you get home?
昨晚
Last night.
-见到你真开心  -我也是
- So good to see you. - Yeah, you too.
除非你是被学校开除的
Unless you failed out of school.
你怎么回来了
Why are you here?
你生日啊
It's your birthday.
我生日
My birthday.
她本来不打算跟我们一起庆祝的
She wasn't planning on celebrating with us,
但现在我们可以在这里开派对了
but now we can have our party here.
小凯会拿便宜酒来的
Kev will bring cheap booze.
非常便宜那种
Like, really cheap.
我可以从超市买个蛋糕
I can pick up a cake from the supermarket.
-我知道你很难受  -谢谢  小黛
- I know this is hard. - Thanks, Debs.
这不是我们的午餐吧
Hope those aren't for us.
恐怕以后要继续吃袋装的了
Back to bag lunches, I'm afraid.
芝士腊肠
Bologna and cheese.
你怎么能突然开始给午餐费  又突然断了
You can't just start giving us lunch money and then cut us off.
我知道  抱歉
I know. I'm sorry.
要是麦克想炒了你  就让他拿出老板的样子
If Mike wants to fire you, make him act like your boss
把这段话写在人事部表格里
and write that shit on a human resource form.
"我辞退这名员工  是因为本来她是跟我打炮的
"I terminated this employee because I was screwing her,
但现在她却跟我兄弟打炮去了"
and then she started screwing my brother."
-什么  -真的吗
- You what? - Really?
我错了  不过说真的
My bad. But seriously,
上述行为完全就是性骚扰啊
this shit is the definition of sexual harassment.
那你是要我若无其事地走进公司
So I'm just gonna go into the office like nothing happened,
承受所有人鄙视的目光吗
with everyone staring at me and hatin' me?
你到底想不想要工资
Do you need the paycheck or not?
按摩床在哪里
Where are the massage tables?
你知道买那玩意儿得多少钱吗
Hey, you know how much those things cost?
看这些  救世军二手店买的  十块一张
Look at this, Salvation Army, 10 bucks each.
只要挂点床单  隔开地方就行
All we gotta do is hang some sheets, divide the space up.
那清理工作呢
Yeah, but what about the cleanup?
怎么了
What about it?
地板上不会全是精液吗
Isn't there gonna be jizz all over the floor?
你想太多了  兄弟
You're over-thinking this, man.
所有东西都备全了
Look, we've got everything we need.
润滑剂  漂白水  量很足
Lube, clorox, all in bulk.
-怎么收费  -五十块  姑娘们分十七
- How much we charge? - 50 bucks, girls get 17.
十七块  那不是跟萨莎一样
17? Same as Sasha?
原来我们至少还有墙呢
At least over there, we have walls.
-还有桌子  -我们学到了一个宝贵的教训
- We have tables. - Yeah, and we learned a valuable lesson
撸管这活儿谁都会
anyone can jerk a cock.
我会  他也会
I jerk mine, he jerks his.
要么学两手绝活儿  要么给老子闭嘴
Learn a unique skill or shut the fuck up.
没人能听懂你他妈在说什么
No one knows what the fuck you're saying.
菲奥娜好啊
Hi, Fiona.
菲奥娜
Fiona.
早上好
Good morning.
能跟我来一下吗  我有事要跟你说
Can you come with me? I need to speak with you.
-出什么事了  -我们还是私下谈比较好
- Everything okay? - Better if we speak privately.
*祝你生日快乐*
*Happy birthday to you*
*祝菲奥娜生日快乐*
*Happy birthday, dear Fiona*
*祝你生日快乐*
*Happy birthday to you*
快许愿吧
Make a wish!
真棒
Attagirl!
快去拿盘子和纸巾吧  我们都饿了
Get some plates and napkins. Come on, we're hungry.
等着吃蛋糕呢
Got some cake to eat!
-你喜欢巧克力吗  -喜欢
- Do you like chocolate? - Yes!
我很想帮你  不过如果伊恩希望你知道
I want to help, but if Ian wanted me to share where he was,
-我早就告诉你了  -他打给你了吗
- you'd already know. - He called you?
我可没这么说
I didn't say that.
你对伊恩的性生活了解多少
What do you know about Ian's sex life?
他喜欢男人
Well, he's gay.
之前他有个老男友
There's an old boyfriend of Ian's.
-多久之前  -不是  我是说年纪大
- From how long ago? - No, I mean like "old" old.
四十多岁吧
Like, over 40.
我不知道他叫什么  不过找到他的话
I don't know his name, but if you find him,
问问他伊恩的事
ask him about Ian.
有消息吗
Anything?
嗯  她说让我们问伊恩的老男友
Yeah, said we should ask Ian's old boyfriend?
一个有白头发的男人
Someone with gray hair?
吉米他爸
Jimmy's dad.
他有次爬上了我的床  硬肉棒戳着我
He crawled into my bed once, poked me with a full chub.
-等等  你是说奈德  -是啊  就他
- Wait, you mean Ned? - Yeah, Ned.
所以吉米他爸是伊恩的男友
Wait, so Jimmy's dad was Ian's boyfriend?
不知道他们的关系到没到那层次
I'm not sure they ever made it to boyfriend status,
不过曼迪说的应该是他
but, yeah, that's who Mandy's talking about.
芝加哥  奈德·里士曼医生
Chicago. Yeah, Dr. Ned Lishman.
快进来吧
Come on in!
奔跑·树  这位是弗兰克的女儿萨咪
Running tree, this is Frank's daughter, Sammi,
还有她儿子恰奇
and her son, Chuck.
抱歉我来晚了  希拉
Sorry I'm late, Sheila.
没找到人帮我照看孩子
I couldn't find anyone to watch the kids.
没关...  什么孩子
Oh, that's no--what kids?
你是把整个部落都带来了  是吧
Brought the whole tribe, did ya?
你  你没跟我说你有孩子呢
Y-you didn't tell me that you had kids.
-从来没提过  -是我姐妹的
- You never mentioned it. - My sister's.
几个月前  她跟瘾君子男友私奔了
She ran off a few months ago with her junkie boyfriend.
你们好啊  欢迎来到这里
Well, hello, and welcome to all of you.
你们叫什么名字呀
What are your names?
这是戴尔  本  莎拉  丹尼斯和加里
This is Dale, Ben, Sarah, Denise, and Gary.
加里你好啊
Hello, Gary.
你的印第安名字叫什么
What's your Indian name?
加里
Gary.
我叫希拉
Oh. Well, I'm Sheila.
只有这一个名字
Just Sheila.
建造汗蒸小屋需要你帮忙
We're gonna need some help building this lodge.
孩子们不管用
These kids are useless.
你需要什么
What do you need?
12根七英尺长的树苗
Well, we need a dozen 7-foot saplings,
24块拳头大小的玄武岩
2 dozen fist-sized basaltic rocks,
柴火  几把铲子  一桶水
kindling, a couple of shovels, a pail of water,
还需要尽量多的防水布  棉被和水牛皮
and all the tarps, quilts, and buffalo skins we can find.
天哪
Jesus.
请进
Come in.
你是要谈公事吧
I assume this is professional in nature?
不是  但我不会打扰你太久的
It's not, but it won't take long.
我能把门关上吗
Can I shut the door?
还是开着吧
I'd prefer you left it open.
世界上最棒的老板
我欠你一个解释
I owe you an explanation,
我的所作所为太疯狂
because what I did was crazy.
我也一直问自己为什么那样做
And I keep asking myself why I did it.
我能想到的唯一答案是
The only answer that I can come up with is that
我想证明一些事
I think I was trying to prove something.
不是向你证明  是向我自己
Not to you, but to myself.
证明我配不上你
Prove that I didn't deserve you...
或是这份工作  以及你的父母和朋友
or this job, your parents, your friends...
配不上所有心地善良  生活规律的正常人
All these nice, normal, functional people.
我真的觉得自己根本不配得到这些
I really didn't think I deserved any of it.
事实证明  我是对的
And in the end, I was right.
说完了
That it?
对
Yeah.
你要开除我吗
Are you firing me?
不  我要把你调任到账户管理部门
No. I am transferring you to account management.
我不做你的顶头上司比较好
I'd prefer you didn't work for me directly.
谢谢你
Thank you.
对了  该说抱歉的是我
I'm the one who's sorry, by the way.
为什么
Why?
抱歉我不够有趣
That I'm not more interesting.
你很有趣
You are.
真的没有
I'm really not.
我有正当工作
I hold down a job,
照顾家人  在意说真话
I look after my family, care about telling the truth.
很抱歉这些并不是亮点
I'm sorry those aren't selling points.
如果你...
Um, if you, uh...
如果可以的话  我想请你离开了
If it's all right, I'd like you to leave now.
你们不是来送寿司的  对吧
You're not delivering my sushi, are you?
恐怕不是
Uh, no, afraid not.
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
我是利普  伊恩的哥哥
Yeah, I'm Lip. Ian's brother.
是哦
Oh, yeah.
哦对
Oh, yeah!
有什么事吗
How can I help you?
恐怕吉米已经很久没联系我了
I'm afraid jimmy hasn't been in touch for a while.
我们是来找伊恩的
We're looking for Ian.
你好啊
Hello!
进来说话吧
Why don't you both come inside?
好  进去吧
Sure, yeah. Go.
知道我气什么吗
Know what pisses me off?
Chris不肯说...
That Chris won't just say--
你们好
Hello.
你喜欢的还真是同一类型啊
You really got a type, huh?
这话什么意思
What does that mean?
他们是伊恩的兄妹
Um, these are Ian's siblings.
好极了  你俩都认识他
Great, so you both know him.
我们上哪能找到他
Where can we find him?
吃的到了我叫你
Um...I'll let you know when the food comes.
好
Okay.
我让伊恩在这儿住过一阵子
I let Ian crash here for a while.
-什么时候  -几周前
- When? - A few weeks ago.
有一天我回到家发现他在招待一群...
Then I came home and he was hosting a group of--
我认为是很讨厌的人
well, in my opinion-unsavory characters.
他们用一瓶野格酒砸烂了我的玻璃桌面
They smashed my glass tabletop with a bottle of jagermeister.
收拾完以后  我就请伊恩离开了
When things settled down, I asked Ian to leave.
他去哪了
Where did he go?
去找你们的妈妈了
Well, he's with your mother.
莫妮卡
Monica?
太好了  他们这会儿在桥洞底下呢
Great, so they're under a bridge somewhere.
是栋屋子
Oh, it was a house.
我还留着地址  你们要吗
I still have the address. You want it?
要
Yeah, please.
小黛  你先回家吧
Hey, Debs, why don't you, uh, why don't you go home, yeah?
为什么
Why?
我们每回找到莫妮卡
Just 'cause every time we find Monica, you know,
都希望没找到她  她也许不知道自己在哪
we wish we hadn't. She might not know where she is,
她是谁  我们是谁
who she is, who we are.
我不是小孩子了
I'm not a little kid.
好吧
Okay.
我可不会花五十块打次手枪
There's no way I'm shelling out 50 bucks for a handjob.
-三十还有可能  -我跟你说
- 30, maybe. - Okay, I'll tell you what.
三十块  你自撸去吧
For 30 bucks, you can go jerk yourself off.
我们有日常开支的  汤米  光是洗衣就...
We've got overhead, Tommy. The laundry alone is killing--
我在泰国妞那儿付三十块
Hey, I pay 30 at the thai place,
她们也洗毛巾
and they wash towels too.
该死的泰国性工作者
Damn thai sex workers,
从正统美国人手里抢生意
stealing jobs from decent Americans.
我们的姑娘是俄罗斯人
Our girls are Russian.
她们用刀叉吃饭
They eat with forks,
又不用筷子吃饭
not with sticks, right?
宝贝  来这儿的每个人你都拉了皮条
Baby, you hit up everyone who's come in here,
三个人都拉了
all three of 'em.
如果我们打打广告呢  在网上或是
What if we advertise? Put an ad in Craigslist
免费的本地商业带发广告
or one of those free local business things?
我们可以找几个瘾君子
Hey, yeah, we can get some meth heads
发传单什么的
to hand out flyers and shit.
-拿什么付他们  -不用付
- And pay them how? - We don't.
跟他们说会给钱
We just tell them we'll pay 'em,
等他们来要钱的时候
and if they complain about it,
就狠揍一顿
we'll beat the shit out of them.
卡尔
Carl!
Carl, hey.
我有个任务要交给你  儿子
I got a job for you, son.
我很忙
I'm busy.
这活儿更好
No, this is--this is better.
我们要搭一座汗蒸小屋
We're gonna build a sweat lodge.
大石头  点篝火  还有帐篷...
Great big rocks, heated by a big fire, and a teepee--
-篝火  -对
- Big fire? - Yeah.
这是萨咪  你大姐
Oh, this is Sammi, your big sister.
该让你们见见了
It's time you met.
我已经有两个姐姐了
I already got two sisters.
这是第三个
Yeah, well, here's another one.
这是你外甥  恰奇
This is your nephew. Chucky,
宝贝  这是你舅舅卡尔
baby, this is your uncle, Carl.
他们长得好像
Wow, they even look alike.
妈的
Oh, shit.
这场面太感人了
This is an emotional situation.
能跟你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you for a second?
-失陪一下  -好
- Excuse us, would you? - Sure.
-我被她吓到了  -我知道
- She's freaking me out. - I get it.
不如我带萨咪去酒吧找人帮忙
Look, how about I take Sammi to the Alibi for reinforcements?
你和恰奇去收集树苗
You and Chuck gather saplings.
你可以带他进加拉格家的门
You can initiate him into the Gallagher way.
等等  树苗是什么东西
Wait, what's a sapling?
你那个男友怎么回事
So what happened with this, uh, boyfriend?
是前男友  他叫马蒂
Ex-boyfriend. His name's Matt.
他人很好  但他说因为我是处
He's nice, but he said we couldn't be together
我们不可以在一起  所以我就跟别人试试...
because I'm a virgin, so I tried it with someone else--
等下  试试
Wait, tried?
做爱
Sex.
跟谁
With who?
赛斯·埃斯帕拉利  在游乐场的厕所里
Seth Esparelli, in the arcade bathroom.
天哪  小黛
Jesus, Debs.
但没成  然后我觉得我跟他算是分手了
Only, it didn't work, and I think we broke up?
我猜是这样
I mean, I guess.
我还没给他打过电话...
I haven't really called him to, like--
-亲口问过  -对  没有
- Confirm? - No--yeah.
压力好大
So stressful.
"这边射"
搞毛
What the hell?
我警告过你别考验我
I warned you not to test me.
-这些人是谁  -我城里网球队的人
- Who are these guys? - My intramural tennis team.
相信我  他们可不是好惹的
And trust me, they do not mess around.
我的钱你准备好了吗
Do you have my cash?
-等下  你们都是基佬吗  -不是
- Wait, are you all gay? - No.
我不是侮辱你们
I'm not trying to be insulting,
就想问问你们  要不要撸一炮
I just want to know if you... want a handjob.
奈德说就是这儿了
Well, Ned said this is the place.
看样子好像没人住
Doesn't look like anyone lives here.
等下  利普  别进去
Wait, Lip, don't go in there.
我也没选择啊  对吧
I kind of have to, right?
来吧  待在我身后
Hey, come on, just stay behind me.
-我们回家吧  -没事的  小黛
- Let's go home. - It's okay, Debs.
有人在用电暖器呢
Someone's got the heat on.
这是伊恩的
This is Ian's.
伊恩
Yo, Ian!
有人来了
Someone's coming.
我靠
Shit.
-不好意思  -我有枪  你们两个混蛋
- Sorry! - I have got a gun, you motherfuckers!
我要把你们打成马蜂窝
I will shoot you full of holes!
别  别这样
No, please don't do that!
我们只是来找兄弟的
We're just looking for our brother!
找谁
Looking for who?
伊恩·加拉格
Ian Gallagher?
或者是莫妮卡  她住这里吗
Or--or Monica? She live here?
你们是谁
Who are you?
-你真的有枪吗  -当然
- Do you really have a gun? - Yeah!
莫妮卡不在这儿住了
And Monica don't live here no more.
好吧  这是我弟弟的东西
Okay, look, this is our brother's stuff, okay?
他住这里的  是吧
So he lives here, right?
我们只是想找到他
Look, we're just trying to find him.
他上班去了
He's at work.
在哪里上班
And where's that?
白燕子俱乐部
The White Swallow.
-等等  什么  -白燕子俱乐部  在男孩城
- Wait, the what? - The White Swallow, in Boystown.
好的  谢谢  谢谢
All right, thank you. Thank you.
走  小黛  走走走
Go, Debs, go. Go, go, go, go, go.
加把劲  快点
Come on, hurry up!
给你  找你的钱
Here you go, here's your change,
维罗妮卡包你舒爽
and Veronica will take care of you.
-正点  -你说啥
- Nice. - Excuse me?
不是她  想得美
No, not her. Forget it.
-米奇  -怎么了
- Mickey! - Yeah?
把这个客人带到楼上吧
Got a customer to take upstairs.
这边  网球高手
Right this way, McEnroe.
艾莱伯酒吧
Alibi.
-是我  -我正想打给你呢
- It's me. - Hey! I was just about to call you.
我们会晚几分钟
We're gonna be a couple of minutes late
这么多天了  酒吧终于有客人了
'cause we have customers at the bar for the first time in days.
我给你打电话是想说
Yeah, I was calling to say
我真的没有心情开派对
I'm not really much in the mood for a party.
太尼玛扫兴了
Well, that's too damn bad,
我和小凯正要带一大瓶
'cause Kev and I are coming over
"伊凡雷帝"伏特加
with a gallon of "Ivan the Terrible" vodka
还有一大筐好吃的立体脆过去呢
and a bucket of cool Ranch Doritos.
要是你不想玩  你就看着
If you don't want to partake, you can watch.
门没关
Door's open!
没得选了吗
I don't have a choice?
拜拜  小骚货
Bye, bitch.
搞什么飞机
Are you kiddin' me?
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
你他妈来这里干什么
What the fuck are you doing here?
我想和你一起庆祝
Well, I thought we could celebrate together.
那我想用笔戳瞎自己的眼睛
Or I could stab myself in the eye with a pencil.
通过道歉的方式
By way of apologizing.
-派对开始  -可卡因
- Now it's a party. - Coke?
刚从戒毒所出来  现在又嗑上了
Fresh out of rehab, and you have coke?
喝酒才是问题
Well, booze is the problem.
我可以嗑可卡因和大麻
I can do coke, a little weed.
不过说到酒的话  我可没有碰
But as far as booze goes, I'm clean.
说话口气真像弗兰克
You sound like Frank.
弗兰克是谁
Who's Frank?
有镜子吗
Oh, you got a mirror?
有  就在这儿
Oh, yeah, right here.
等下  这个是球棒
Oh, wait, it's a baseball bat.
别这样  淡定
Hey! Whoa, easy, easy.
行吧
Okay, okay.
生日快乐
All right. Happy birthday.
他知道是我们吗
Does he know it's us?
应该知道吧
Yeah, I think so.
你们好啊
What's up?
嘿  老哥
Hey, man.
黛比
Debbie!
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
-你看起来真棒  -谢谢
- You look great! - Thank you.
你也是
You do too.
这是我哥哥和妹妹
This is my brother and sister.
是我的家人
This is family!
你在这里干多久了
Hey, how long you been working here, huh?
-几个星期了  -是吗
- A couple weeks. - Yeah?
这地方帅呆了
This place, it's awesome.
超级方便
It's--it's super convenient.
你俩想喝点什么  我请客
You guys want drinks? They're on the house.
-不用  没事  -苹果马提尼
- No, I'm good, I'm good. - Appletini, appletin--
-不用了  -两杯苹果马提尼
- No. - Two appletinis.
好的
Okay.
伊恩  有别的地方可以谈话吗
Hey, Ian, is there any place we could talk?
我爱死这首歌了
Oh, I love this song!
几个军队宪兵正在找你
Yeah, look, some army M.P.s came by looking for you.
他们要以擅离职守罪
They want to arrest you for going AWOL,
-和盗窃政府财产罪逮捕你  -高级货色
- stealing government property. - This is top-shelf.
听到我说话了吗
No, hey, did--did you hear me?
他们说你偷了一架直升机
They say you stole a helicopter.
太可笑了
That's hilarious.
是吗
Is it?
是啊  我什么都没偷
Yeah, yeah, I mean, I didn't steal anything,
我只是发动了一下
I just started the rotors.
你俩能在这里待会儿吗
Hey, can you guys hang around for a while?
我两点钟交班
My shift gets off at 2:00,
之后我都会出去玩  或者健个身
but I always go out after, or hit the local gym,
要看我有多累了
depending on how pumped I am.
但是见到了你们  我感觉太棒了
But seeing you guys, I-I just-- I feel great, you know?
好吧  要不我们去外边
Okay, you know what, hey, let's go outside
这样可以互相听清楚  好吗
so we can hear each other, huh?
-尝尝吧  -不  出去
- Try your drink. - No, outside.
来吧  过来
Come on, come here.
-把你的手拿开  -没关系  没事的
- Hey, get your hand off him. - No, it's fine, it's okay.
我们是兄弟  在聊天呢  嘿  伊恩
We're brothers, all right? We're just talking. Yo, Ian!
我还要看你的身份证
And I definitely need some I.D.
-过来  伊恩  -快走
- Come on, Ian! - Let's go!
她没喝酒  伙计  伊恩
She's not drinking, man. Ian!
他为什么要这样
Why was he acting like that?
已经很晚了  我们走吧
It's late. We should go.
他出什么事了吗
Is there something wrong with him?
至少我们知道他在哪里了  是吧
At least we know where he is now, okay?
我会再回来看他的
I'll come back and check on him.
我们回家吧  好吗
Let's get you home, though, all right?
走吧
Come on.
这个会让你们感觉是在自己家里
This is gonna make you feel right at home.
好了
Okay.
我做了豆煮玉米  藜麦
I've got succotash, quinoa, and frybread
和橡子粉油炸面包  都是原住民菜
made from acorn powder, indigenous to our people.
你叫什么来着
What was your name again?
独眼蛇
One-eyed Snake.
这是恶臭风
And this is Stinking Wind.
恶臭风
Stinking Wind.
挺特别的
That's unusual.
有汉堡吗
Got any burgers?
布法罗汉堡  我这儿有布法罗汉堡
Buffalo burgers. I've got Buffalo burgers.
想吃吗  我给你拿
Would you like that? Let me get that for you.
等一下
Hold on a second.
稍等  小姑娘  稍等
Hold on, hold on, missy, hold on.
傻叉  为什么要用假名
Dumb shit, why are you giving her fake names?
因为她疯疯癫癫的
'Cause she's crazy.
至少她给我们做了晚餐
At least she made us dinner.
绑紧了  结实点
Tie it tight. Nice and tight.
-好  很好  -我们回来了
- Yeah, good, good. - Yeah, we made it!
我靠
Holy shit.
爸  爸  爸爸
Dad, dad, dad, dad, dad.
快看我们的成果
Look what we built.
我们从芝加哥警局门口偷来的树
We took it from a whole pile of trees
然后我们用...
from the PDC, and then we got--
萨咪太厉害了
Sammi was amazing!
她跟酒吧的人说  印第安小屋能治不举
She rallied the bar by telling them the lodge
一帮人就来帮忙了  之后还带头偷了
would cure impotence, and then she led the charge
贫民窟流浪汉的毯子
to steal blankets from the bums on skid row.
真是虎父无犬女
Is she a chip off the old block or what?
都是为了造福人间
All for a good cause.
老天  这些毯子臭死了
Jesus, they reek.
能防止热气外泄就行
Yeah, well, they'll keep the heat in.
来吧  各位  我们走起
Come on, guys, let's go.
好了  艾伦  这里是350块
All right, Alan, here's $350.
剩下的过几天给你
I'll give you the rest in a couple of days.
凯文  对于将我老爸的公寓
You know, Kevin, the idea of men upstairs,
变成满地精液的地方
jizzing all over dad's apartment...
我觉得  赞
works for me.
跟你朋友宣传宣传
Tell your friends, okay?
好了  宝贝  剩下的事交给笛图
All right, babe, let Tito here take over.
-我们得去菲奥娜家了  -好  我再喝一杯
- We got to get to Fiona's. - All right, just one more shot.
敬老派的美国资本主义
Here's to good old fashioned American Capitalism.
尽管它给男人准备了种种艰难险阻
You can keep a man down.
但它永远无法阻止小兄弟要站起来的愿望
But you can never keep him from getting it up.
说得好
Yes, sir!
走吧  走吧
Let's go, let's go!
酋长说要把所有的洞都堵起来
Chief says cover all the holes, come on.
爸爸  萨咪小的时候  你有没有想过她
Dad, when Sammi was little, did you ever think about her?
当然有
Of course I did.
其实没有  但主要是她妈的错
Well, no, I didn't, but that had more to do with her mother.
她是个烦人精
She was a real pain in the ass.
怎么说
How come?
她想要我找份工作  养家糊口什么的
She wanted me to...get a job, support them, yada, yada, yada.
你现在几岁  十岁吗
How old are you now, ten?
-十二岁  -儿子  要不了多久
- 12. - Well, soon you'll knock up
你就会搞大第一个穷妹子的肚子  然后抛弃她
your first ghetto girl and ditch her.
等你活到我这岁数  就知道要看远点
But, you get to my age, you get perspective.
你会学着接受那些为人父母
You learn to embrace the responsibilities
所带来的责任
that come with parenthood.
萨咪是我最后一次好好表现的机会了
Sammi's my last chance to get it right.
什么叫"好好表现"
What do you mean, "get it right"?
什么
Huh?
我得走了
I gotta go.
现在吗  那你会错过仪式的
Now? You're gonna miss the ceremony.
再见
See ya.
等我把这些滚烫的石头
Soon as I carry these hot rocks
放进小屋  一切就准备妥当了
into the lodge, we're ready.
你没事吧
You okay?
我儿子刚刚跑了
My son just took off.
看看我姐妹的小孩
Huh, look at my sister's kids.
我们在外面搭这该死的传统汗蒸小屋
We're out here building a traditional fucking sweat lodge,
他们却在里面跷脚看电视  去他们的
they're in there watching TV fuck 'em.
快看利亚姆的舞步
Liam's breakin' it down!
就算不能喝酒  不能嗑药也没关系
I don't care if I can't drink or take your drugs!
老娘有多力多滋  多力多滋就像可卡因
I got Doritos! Doritos are like crack!
也许直接吸入也行
I might even snort 'em.
至少罗比把生日礼物送对了  那个混球
Well, at least Robbie got one thing right, the prick.
菲奥娜  快过来
Fiona, get your ass in here!
让你瞧瞧老娘的摆臀舞
I'm gonna show you how to break it down!
来了
Coming.
进去吧
Okay, go on.
小黛
Hey, Debs.
谢谢你今天陪我一起
Thanks for coming with me today.
谢谢你让我跟着
Yeah, thanks for letting me.
看看利普
Look at Lip now!
有蛋糕  有蛋糕  有蛋糕
Cake, cake, cake, cake!
你去哪了
Where you been?
参加了一次小探险
Oh, we just on a little adventure.
晚点再跟你细说
I'll tell you all about it later.
看样子我的饭碗保住了
Well, looks like somebody's gonna get to keep their job!
真的假的  太棒了
Oh, no shit, that's great.
菲奥娜
Fiona!
-天呐  -怎么了
- Oh, my God. - What?
-糟了  -他脸上的是什么
- Oh, shit. - What's on his face?
天呐  天呐  天呐
Oh, my God, oh, my God, oh, my God.
-退后  退后  -天呐
- Step back, step back. - Oh, my God.
-往后退  -他没呼吸了
- Step back. - He's not breathing!
-天呐  -天呐
- Oh, my God. - Oh, my God.
-天呐  天呐  -利亚姆  醒醒
- Oh, my God, oh, my God. - Liam? Liam? Liam?
-天呐  叫救护车  -利亚姆
- Oh, my God, call! - Liam?
利亚姆  退后  给他一点空间
Liam? Step back, give him some room.
利亚姆
Liam?
-天呐  -利亚姆
- Oh, my God. - Liam?
血压200/120  心率每分钟130次
BP. is 200 over 120. Heart rate's 130.
他摄入了什么
What'd he take?
可卡因  他吸了我的可卡因
Coke! He got into my coke.
-吸了多少  -半克或者更多
- How much? - A half gram, maybe more.
我不知道
I don't know.
-人过来了  -他不会有事吧
- Coming through. - He gonna be okay?
他不会有事的  对吧
He's gonna be okay, though, right?
请让开
Yeah, clear the way, please.
人过来了
Coming through!
三岁的男童  误食可卡因
Three-year-old male, cocaine ingestion.
血压200/120  心率每分钟130次
BP's 200 over 120. HR is 130.
-他不会有事的  对吧  -已用2毫克
- He's gonna be okay, right? - Started 2 milligrams
劳拉西泮  昏迷12分钟
of ativan, 12 minutes out.
他不会有事的  对吧
He's gonna be okay, right?
我去把卡车开来
I'll get the truck.
感谢您  大神  感谢您的保佑
Thank you, great spirit, for this blessing,
感谢赐予我们土壤  植物  树木
for the good earth, plants, and trees.
我们的汗水是万能的生命线
The universal lifeblood of our sweat
与世界之水交融
intermingles with the waters of the world,
将它送向四面八方
carried to the four quarters of the planet.
治愈之灵  当你在我们身边时我们能感受到你
We know you, healing spirit, when you are with us.
你的声音就是万物的声音
Your voice is the voice of all things.
-你召唤我们...  -弗兰克·加拉格
- You call to us-- - Frank Gallagher!
我的妈呀
Jesus Christ!
这里好热
Wow, it's hot.
弗兰克在这里吗
Hey, is Frank in here?
他儿子利亚姆出事了
It's about his son, Liam.
-爸  -5533号需要救护车
- Dad? - Beat 5533, I need an ambulance.
他们不让我进去
They won't let me back there.
在派对上我有看着他
I was watching him at the party.
本以为他在客厅的
I thought he was in the living room.
打扰一下  叫利亚姆  利亚姆·加拉格的小孩
Excuse me, Liam? Liam Gallagher?
先坐一下
Have a seat.
马上会有人出来找你的
Someone will be out with you in a minute.
什么意思
What was that?
菲奥娜是哪位
Who's Fiona?
是我
That's me.
把双手放到身后
Put your hands behind your back.
什么
What?
菲奥娜·加拉格  你有权保持沉默
Fiona Gallagher, you have the right to remain silent.
搞什么  出什么事了
Whoa, whoa, whoa, what's going on?
但是你所说的一切  都将成为呈堂证供
Anything you say can and will be used against you in a court of law.
你有权聘请律师
You have the right to an attorney.
如果无法负担这笔费用
If you cannot afford one,
法院将会为你指派一名辩护律师
one will be appointed to you.
你明白自己的权利了吗
Do you understand your rights as I've read them to you?